If your purpose is your why, your vision is your where.
Now, a common question we get is, do I need one M.V.P. blueprint for my personal life
and then another for my professional life? The answer is no. An athlete leads one integrated life.
It's important to know that drafting this vision takes time and you should expect to have
several iterations. Don't aim for perfection. Aim for progress because when you get clear on your
vision and you're able to share it, it builds a powerful foundation of trust with your team.
Your vision is the ability to look ahead and see with vivid detail the future you're working to
create. It's the destination of your leadership map. A vision isn't a vague dream like,
I want to be successful. It's a clear written declaration. A powerful vision is sensory.
What do you see? What do you hear? Who is around you? How do you feel? For example,
a vision statement might be, in five years I will be leading a global team recognized as an expert
in sustainable technology while maintaining the flexibility of being fully present for my family.
It's specific. It's aspirational. It provides daily motivation. When the day-to-day work gets
tough, when you face a setback, you can close your eyes and see the vision. It reminds you
of what you're fighting for. It's what helps an athlete push through that last painful mile of
that marathon. They aren't thinking about the pain. They're visualizing the final finish line.
In your playbook, you will use the reflections you did in lesson two on your desire to feature
state to draft a powerful vision statement. Now, don't be afraid to dream big. An athlete's
vision should stretch them. It should pull you forward.